Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have a special
dialogue for you all
about this important
test that you need for
going to graduate school.
That's right.
Today we're going to talk about
the famous or very scary GMAT.
Alright so the GMAT,
GMAT is the test that
students will take when
they want to go to graduate
school for business
management, so an MBA program.
That's right and it's a pretty much a
standard test that you have to take as you say
to get into one of
these programs and so
today we're going to
talk a little bit about
the sections of the test
and more or less how
it's structured but
not too much in depth.
That's right so let's take a listen to
our dialogue, we'll be back in a moment.
I can't seem to progress
up the career ladder
no matter how hard I try and I
have been here for two years already.
Well have you thought of getting an MBA?
I heard it does wonders
in getting you to the top.
An MBA hey well my
degree wasn't in business,
the business schools
won't be interested in me.
Nonsense, the business schools measure
your ability through a test called GMAT.
GMAT, what does that stand
for and what will the test contain?
Graduate Management Admission Test.
It contains three
parts, analytical writing
assessment, the quantitative
section and the verbal section.
Not only does the test
score you on the number
of questions answered
but also on the difficulty.
Okay this sounds a little tough, how
am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you.
You could have a one-on-one
session with a tutor or a group sessions.
You can also use free
or private computer
software, going to
church might help as well.
No matter what I do
I'm going to ace this
test and go on to
become a corporate fat cap.
That's the spirit.
Alright we're back
so now let's talk about
some of the language we
found on language take away.
Language take away.
Alright so there's a
lot of great stuff here.
The first one we've got is actually
more about a job than school.
This is the career ladder.
That's right Ash is
complaining how he can't
seem to make any
progress in the career ladder.
So what is a career ladder?
Well we know what a
ladder is, a ladder is a
tool that you use to climb
from a low place to a high place.
So for example if you want to go on the
roof of your house you have to use a ladder.
A career ladder is,
it's like an analogy you
know when you start a career you start at
the bottom and you climb up up to the top.
So going from the bottom to maybe
the president of an organization.
So that's called the career ladder.
Yeah climbing from
the bottom of a career
area like for example
being the male man in an
office building to being
the president of that office.
So this is what Ash
is complaining about
that it's hard or he
can't really seem to go
up the career ladder.
And so Mindy suggests that he should
take the GMAT and go into graduate school.
So as we said the GMAT is a test
that you take but what is it stand for?
What is GMAT?
GMAT stands for Graduate
Management Admission Test.
Okay so that's the test that you
take when you want to go to school.
So you have to send
your scores to the
admissions office of the
school you want to go
to and they will decide if
they're high enough or not.
Okay very good.
So not everyone can go
to graduate school and
you have to take this
test and pass it basically.
Well there's no pass
fail but certain schools
will say that a score
is high enough and
other schools will say that a
higher score is more important.
So you can maybe go to a better
school if you have a better score.
And well Mindy went on to
explain the three parts of this test.
The first one she said
is analytical writing.
Alright so analytical writing is
a very common part of a test.
For example I think the
SAT also has analytical
writing and basically you're asked to
read something and then write about it.
And analytical means that you have to
really use your mind to make an argument.
It's not just read and
repeat, read and repeat.
So it basically comes from analyzing.
Yes.
You analyze what you read
and then you write about it.
That's what you have to think.
And you have to
understand what you read and
then you have to write
something that makes sense.
It's logical.
Do you put your opinion
in analytical writing?
No.
It's based on facts.
Based on facts and logic and argument.
Okay.
So you have this part
of analytical writing
and Mindy talks about the
quantitative section of the test.
So what is this?
So the quantitative
section you think of the
word quantify, quantity,
quantitative has to do with numbers.
Okay.
So you have to be able
to understand basic math,
some algebra, some arithmetic,
some statistics, for example.
So quantitative sections on
tests are the math sections.
Now from my
understanding, even though it
is a math section,
it's not really like they
give you a problem in
equation and you have to solve it.
It's more like analysis, right?
They give you some information
and you have to use math to solve it.
That's right.
So there are a number of different parts.
One of them is like
what you say it's kind of
it's about logic while using
algebra to solve these problems.
I think the other part
of it has to do with
statistics and being able to understand
trends, graphs, things like that.
So this is the math section of the exam.
So not only do you
have to be able to read,
understand, and analyze what you're reading,
you have to be able to be good at math.
And then finally, we have a verbal section.
What is this all about?
This is about your English
language and grammar skills.
And so the verbal section will
test your vocabulary knowledge.
Do you understand what big words mean?
Also will test your ability to
read passages and analyze them.
So I guess this part is
one of the most important
parts for foreign
students who obviously
don't speak English
as their first language,
that this makes sure
that you have a good
enough English level to be able to
take a graduate program in English, right?
Part of it's that there's
a special test that
will test your English
abilities, but this
is absolutely an important part for a
non-native English speaker on the GMAT.
You have to, it's hard for English
speakers who are born speaking English.
You know, you're native
English speakers, yeah.
So it's something that
really you should devote
your time to if you
are non-native English
speaker because there will be
some very challenging words there.
Okay.
So those are the three
sections of the GMAT.
And so to finish off
language takeaway, Ash
said that he's going
to take this test because
he wants to become
a corporate fat cat.
All right.
Now this is an interesting term.
This is not something
we talk about in the office.
This is something we
talk about with friends.
So a corporate fat cat, you think corporate
corporation is has to do business.
So basically we're talking
about very important
businessmen, but fat cat's
not a good thing, right?
No, it's not really.
You refer to a fat cat, a corporate fat cat
is a businessmen who you consider to have
a lot of money, but
obviously you make the
analogy that they're fat because
they have so much money.
And it's kind of a
way of saying that the
businessmen are not the corporate
fat cats are not the best people around.
No, you're basically
saying that these guys,
these men on top, they're
rich, but they're kind of lazy.
And so he wants to be a corporate fat cat.
He wants to be very rich and
powerful and not have to work so hard.
Which obviously is not
really the case always,
but this is a common
term that, as you said,
you wouldn't really
mention it in the office,
but it's more of a satirical way
of speaking about businessmen.
All right.
So now let's finish off
language takeaway and
move on to some
phrases on Fluency Builder.
I can't seem to progress
up the Creoletta no
matter how hard I try and I have
been here for two years already.
Well, have you thought of getting an MBA?
I heard it does wonders
and getting you to the top.
An MBA, hey?
Well, my degree wasn't in business.
The business schools
won't be interested in me.
Nonsense.
The business schools measure your
ability through a test called GMAT.
GMAT?
What does that stand for
and what will the test contain?
Graduate Management Admission Test.
It contains three parts.
Analytical writing assessment, the
quantitative section, and the verbal section.
Not only does the test
score you on the number of
questions answered,
but also on the difficulty.
Okay, this sounds a little tough.
How am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you.
You could have a one-on-one
session with a tuner or group sessions.
You can also use free or
private computer software.
Going to church might help as well.
No matter what I do,
I'm going to ace this
test and go on to
become a corporate fat cap.
Ah, that's the spirit.
Alright, influencey-building today.
We have a number of really
great phrases you can use the first.
The first one is from Mindy.
She says, "I heard it does
wonders in getting you to the top."
Right.
She suggests getting an MBA.
I heard it does wonders
to improve your career.
Alright, this is actually something
that you might hear in a commercial.
It does wonders, means it really helps.
It's really beneficial to you.
Right.
You might hear in a commercial,
for example, with a face cream.
It does wonders to your skin.
It really makes your skin look good.
So by using this phrase, it does wonders.
You're basically saying
it's fast, defective.
It's almost a miracle of how
much it can improve your career
or in this case of the cream,
how it can improve your face.
That's right.
So the MBA does wonders.
It's almost miraculous how positive
and effective it will have in your career.
Exactly.
Okay.
It does wonders.
And then Ash was asking that
how he's supposed to study for this.
And Mindy answered, "Well, you know what?
It's up to you.
You have a lot of options.
So up to you.
" Up to you.
This means it's your decision.
Okay.
So we can use this in normal life.
You know, you know,
you and I are out, Marco
and I say, "Well, I
don't know what to eat.
What do you want to eat?
" Like I say, "Oh, whatever.
It's up to you.
" Up to me.
That means I get to decide what we eat.
And I want pizza.
Okay.
Very good.
So up to you is a way to say, "No.
You decide.
" Mm-hmm.
It's up to you.
It's your decision.
Okay.
And for our next phrase,
Ash was saying that
he's going to study really hard
and he's going to ace the test.
All right.
Now to ace a test.
This is a phrase that we use.
We can use it in high school and
college as well, not just MBA programs.
And to ace a test means
to do perfectly on it.
Okay.
That means to get an A or even 100%.
So it's important to remember that
we have this grading system A, B, C, D, F.
A is the top.
All right.
And so you ace it means you don't make
any mistakes, and remember that A for ace.
Okay.
So you can even use it if it's not
really a test like a job interview.
You say, "I aced
that job interview.
" I ace it.
And in sports, oftentimes
we see this tennis.
It's a sports analogy.
Tennis, when someone serves a ball and the
other player can't even hit the ball back.
It's an ace.
You get a point.
That's right.
So it's a ace for that or even good
sports athletes do call them aces.
Aces.
So after a job interview, I can say,
"Wow, Marco, I really aced that interview.
I aced it.
" Okay.
And Mindy says, "Well, you know what?
That's really good.
That's the spirit.
" That's the spirit.
Now, this is something you say to
someone when you like their attitude.
Okay.
So if I say, "Oh man, I did really bad.
This is stupid.
I don't want to study.
" Mm-hmm.
You say, "Well, that's the bad attitude."
Right.
But if I say, "You know what?
I'm going to do awesome.
This is great.
I'm so I'm going to kill this.
I'm going to ace it.
" No, you could
say, "That's the spirit.
That's the spirit.
That means good attitude.
That's the right way
to think about this.
" So you're kind of even
encouraging that person.
You're saying, "You know what?
I really like your attitude.
That's the good way of thinking.
" Exactly.
So if you want to push
someone and say, "Good for you.
This is a good
way to approach it.
" You say, "That's the spirit.
" Okay.
Awesome.
So this is all the language
that we have for fluency builder.
Why don't we take a break
and we'll be right back.
I can't seem to
progress up the Creole at
an no matter how hard I try, and I
have been here for two years already.
Well, have you thought of getting an MBA?
I heard it does wonders
and getting you to the top.
An MBA, hey?
Well, my degree wasn't in business.
The business schools
weren't being trusted in me.
nonsense.
The business schools measure your
ability through a test called GMAT.
GMAT, what does that stand
for and what will the test contain?
Graduate Management Admission Test.
It contains three parts,
analytical writing assessment,
the quantitative section,
and the verbal section.
Not only does the test
score you on the number of
questions answered,
but also on the difficulty.
Okay.
This sounds a little tough.
How am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you.
You could have a one-on-one
session with a tuner or group sessions.
You can also use free or
private computer software.
Going to church might help as well.
No matter what I do,
I'm going to ace this
test and go on to
become a corporate fat cap.
That's the spirit.
Alright, we're back.
So now talking about the GMAT and an MBA.
This seems to be a very
popular topic nowadays.
Everyone wants to
get obviously a good
education and go to
graduate school, which means
getting your master's degree
or your doctoral degree.
What do you think about
the GMAT and the MBA?
Is it a miracle worker like
this girl says she does well?
Does wonders for your career,
do you think that's really the case?
I don't know.
Maybe if you asked me
five years ago, I would
say yes, but I really believe
that it depends on the person.
Nothing is a miracle cure.
I do think that if you
really have a good
attitude and you work
hard, you'll get a lot out of it.
But if you think it's
going to get you a job,
you're wrong because you
have to get yourself a job.
So I think it depends on the person.
Now obviously also it
depends on the country,
right now, how popular
or how important
is it for people to
have a, let's say, an MBA
to get ahead in business
in the United States?
I'd say it's pretty important.
You don't have to have an MBA.
I mean, you can start your
own business and if you're
successful, you'll probably
start more businesses.
But getting an MBA is also
a very good opportunity
to network, to meet
people, to find out
more about the industry
that you want to start out in.
So I think in that sense
it's pretty important
because it's a way to
start making contacts.
Yeah, you definitely
meet a lot of people with
work experience, from different
backgrounds, international students.
So it's obviously a
great thing, but obviously
to be able to do one
of these programs,
like get an MBA, you
have to take these tests,
which I understand
are very, very difficult.
They are very difficult and
it can be very expensive.
I mean, graduate school itself is $100,
$200,000, and then to prepare for the tests,
you could spend another $1,000
just getting classes or tutoring.
So I do think that it can be a lot of money
up front, but there are places that you
can go to to study and you could even
study on your own using your computer.
Yeah, exactly.
I think this is a very
interesting topic because
in many different
cultures, in many different
places, education,
or for example, higher
learning, like getting an MBA,
has different levels of importance.
Like in Europe, a lot of
Europeans maybe don't
really even pay too much
attention to getting an MBA.
Whereas in other
countries, they might really
emphasize like you
have to have an MBA.
It's really good.
It's going to be good for your career.
So it's very interesting to see how
in different places they handle it.
It is interesting.
And I'm actually very
curious to hear from our users.
Have you ever thought about getting an MBA?
Or MBA is important to
do business in your country.
Let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.